Off season training for football; outdoor conditioning.
Right now we are going to do another superset, a combination of burpies and sit-ups.
Jones is going to demonstrate what a burpie is.
Can we take it slow real fast?
We want to hit the ground and then jump back into a plank position lowered down for a push-up and then we're going to spring forward and then get into a squat, deep squat position and then we finish by ending up on top.
Then we are going to combine that with sit-ups.
Can you show us some sit-ups, please?
Jones is showing us what we mean about sit-ups.
We are going to work full sit-ups so that we're getting the hip flexors involved and when we come up on top we open up the chest, open up the shoulders and push the chest out.
Now we are going to work a combination of it.
Jones is going to take it at full speed.
We're working down and up.
We're going to do ten and ten.
He's going to do ten burpies.
We're going to do five and five.
We're going to do a combination of five burpies for ten sit-ups.
We want to repeat this for five sets.
We'll be doing five burpies and ten sit-ups each set for a total of twenty-five burpies and fifty sit-ups.
That's for our superset of burpies and sit-ups.
Next we are going to work on some exercises, single leg exercises that will help develop stability and agility.